Guide to the Urban League of Pittsburgh Records, 1915-1963 AIS.1981.11
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Urban League of Pittsburgh Records
1915-1963
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Urban League of Pittsburgh
AIS.1981.11
12.5 Linear Feet (10 boxes)
The records of the Urban League of Pittsburgh, founded in 1918, contain minutes, correspondence, department reports, photographs and Urban League Fellows theses from 1915-1963. The emphasis of the Urban League was on African-American employment and training; topics include federal housing projects, youth employment, worker discrimination and African-American welfare work. Digital reproductions of selected images are available online.
History
In 1917, John T. Clark surveyed the needs of Pittsburgh's African-American community of the by bringing the National Urban League to Pittsburgh. In 1918, Dr. Francis Tyson and the Pittsburgh Council for Social Services Among Negroes asked that Clark establish an Urban League branch in Pittsburgh (505 Wylie Avenue).
The Board of the Pittsburgh Council became the first executive board members of the Urban League. Some of its active members were Dr. Francis Tyson of the University of Pittsburgh; Robert L. Vann, Editor of the Pittsburgh Courier and Walter A. May of the May Drug Company, who became the first board president.
During World War I, African-Americans migrated North to Pittsburgh seeking work in the mills and factories. The League helped to provide housing, sanitary conditions and work for the African-American masses. In the 1923 Directory of the Philanthropic Social and Civic Agencies of the City of Pittsburgh, the goals of the Urban League of Pittsburgh were cited as: "Renders social service to Negroes through work in Courts with delinquents; in homes with a Home Economics service; Girl's Clubs in various parts of the city; Home and School visiting service, and especially the Industrial problems of Negroes throughout the Pittsburgh District."
The Urban League expanded its activities through the Depression of the 1930's and World War II to include health, education, home economics and industrial welfare. In the 1933 edition of the directory, known in that year under the title, Directory of Social Agencies of Pittsburgh and Allegheny County, the purpose of the organization was noted as: "Renders social service to Negroes through programs with junior and adult clubs in various parts of the city; home and school visiting service; and especially in dealing with the Industrial problems of Negroes throughout the Pittsburgh district; operates employment bureau; program largely educational, with speakers on current inter-racial matters furnished various groups; acts as consultant on matters regarding the relations between the races. In 1939, a summer camp for African-American youth was established, Camp James Weldon. The growth of government spending and programs led to one of the most active times for the League and provided new opportunities for Pittsburgh's African-American community. The League began to enroll African-Americans in government programs and assisted with overcoming the discrimination of unions and businesses."
The 1950 edition of the Directory of Social Agencies of Pittsburgh and Allegheny County gave as the organization's purpose: "To conduct a social service program including vocational guidance, employment, educational and recreational work and neighborhood groups designed to improve the conditions under which Negroes in Allegheny County may live, work and play." The League was especially concerned about the industrial problems faced by many African-Americans in Pittsburgh. As a way to confront the issue the League created a specialized employment bureau. This program was largely educational that involved speakers who spoke on current inter-racial matters common in the work-place. The bureau acted as a consultant to African-American workers on matters regarding race-relations and cooperated with governmental agencies to ensure African-American participation on the basis of equality.
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of the collection are available electronically at http://historicpittsburgh.org/collection/urban-league-pittsburgh-records.
Scope and Content Notes
The records of the Urban League of Pittsburgh, founded in 1918, contain minutes, correspondence, department reports, photographs and Urban League Fellows theses from 1915-1963, with a concentration of materials between 1918-1945. Many of the records were destroyed in a fire that occurred in the League offices in 1945. The collection is divided into 8 series according to subject and are arranged chronologically and alphabetically. The strength of the collection concerns African-American employment and training. Topics such as federal housing projects, youth employment, worker discrimination and African-American welfare work. The records contain extensive material about the National Urban League, Negro Industrial Welfare Workers, National Vocation Opportunity Campaign and Camp Weldon Johnson. The photographs separated from the general collection maintain the file numbers present in this finding aid.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research but because of the fragile nature of the materials strict supervision on handling is required.
Acquisition Information
Donated by the Urban League of Pittsburgh in 1981.
Previous Citation
Urban League of Pittsburgh Records, 1915-1963, AIS.1981.11, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Urban League of Pittsburgh, Records, 1917-1968, AIS 81:11, Archives of Industrial Society, University Library System, Hillman Library, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pa
African Americans -- Medical care -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; African Americans -- Pennsylvania; Pennsylvania -- Social conditions; Education; Social action; Ethnic groups; Associations; Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Social conditions; African Americans -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Programs (Documents); Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Pennsylvania; Housing -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Charities -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Public welfare -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Social service -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Unemployment -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Education -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Discrimination -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; African Americans -- Housing -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; African Americans -- Employment -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; African Americans -- Civil rights -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; African Americans -- Health and hygiene -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; African Americans -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Societies and clubs; African Americans -- Social conditions; Race discrimination -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Medical care -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Home economics -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Industrial relations -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Recreation -- Pennsylvania; Sports -- Pennsylvania; Recreation -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Sports -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; National Urban League; Urban League of Pittsburgh; Urban League of Pittsburgh. Executive Board; Urban League of Pittsburgh. Industrial Welfare Department
- Executive Board, I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Series I, Executive Board, consists of correspondence, reports, minutes, and memoranda, from 1917-1942, arranged chronologically except for the committee series, which is arranged alphabetically by committee. The Executive Board of the Pittsburgh Urban League oversees all activities of the League staff and committees oversee the League Departments. All social welfare activities performed by the League, along with daily operations, are represented in the records.
  - Administrative Material, 1.
    - Correspondence, 1920-1942 (Box 1, Folder 1-18)
    - Minutes, 1917-1941 (Box 1, Folder 19-33)
    - Reports, 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Membership, 1928-1941 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - President's Report, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Executive Committees, 2.
    - Membership Committee, 1926-1937 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Adult Education Committee, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Budget Committee, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Case Work Policy Committee, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Civic Committee, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Consititution Committee, 1925-1926 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Contact Committee, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Defense Committee, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Delinquency Committee, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - East End Parent's Committee, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Education Committee, 1924-1938 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Negro Emergency Relief Committee, 1920-1929 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Finance Committee, 1926-1930 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Finance Committee, Fund Raising, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Health Committee, 1925-1933 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Home Community Committee, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Home Economics Committee, 1922-1925 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Industry Committee, Minutes, 1926-1944 (Box 2, Folder 54-56)
    - Industry Committee, Membership, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Industry Committee, Meetings, Announcements, 1942-1944 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Industry Committee, Correspondence, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Interracial Committee, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Job Mobilization Campaign Committee, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Library Office Service Committee, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Nominating Committee, 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Public Education Committee, 1932-1934 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Publicity Committee, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Race Relations Committee, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Temporary Education Committee, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Visiting Teacher Committee, 1931-1937 (Box 2, Folder 68-69)
- Departments, II.
  Series II, Departments, contains correspondence, applications, reports, publications, clippings, and memoranda. The actual work if the League was carried out by its various departments. As the League grew in membership and influence, so did its activities. A department was created for each new area of activity and a secretary provided oversight. The Industrial Department was the largest; its responsibilities included worker placement, welfare work in the plants, liaison with companies and efforts to achieve union membership for African-American workers. Other departments were concerned with health, recreation, home economics, education, and clubs. The files span the years 1918-1945 and are arranged in two sub-series. The first is an alphabetical arrangement of all departments except the Industrial Department. The second sub-series is the Industrial Department.
  - General Departments, 1.
    - Civic Department, 1930-1932 (Box 2, Folder 70-71)
    - Club Worker Department, 1926-1928 (Box 2, Folder 72-75)
    - Education Department, 1931-1941 (Box 2, Folder 76-78)
    - Fine Arts Department (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Home Economics Department, 1919-1925 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Home School Department, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Information and Advice, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - All Embracing Musical Group, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Recreation Department, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Toy Library, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Industrial Department, 2.
    - Administrative Material
      - Directors, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 86)
      - Correspondence, 1919-1945 (Box 3, Folder 87-92)
    - Companies
      - Major War Plants, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 93)
      - Names and Addresses, 1920-1927 (Box 3, Folder 94)
      - Allis-Chalmers, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 95)
      - American Sheet Tin, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 96)
      - American Steel Wire, 1918-1923 (Box 3, Folder 97)
      - Carnegie Steel, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 98)
      - Carnegie Illinois Steel, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 99)
      - Consolidated Coal, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 100)
      - Curtis Wright, Greyhound Bus, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 101)
      - Freemont Foundry, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 102)
      - G.M. Johnson, North Dakota (Box 3, Folder 103)
      - Jones Laughlin Steel, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 104)
      - Keystone Picture Frame, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 105)
      - Lockhart Iron and Steel, 1918-1921 (Box 3, Folder 106)
      - Mellon Stuart, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 107)
      - National Malleable Castings, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 108)
      - Pittsburgh Coal, 1933-1938 (Box 3, Folder 109)
      - Standard Sanitary, 1920-1921 (Box 3, Folder 110)
      - Westinghouse, Electric, 1918-1923 (Box 3, Folder 111-112)
      - Westinghouse, Air Brake, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 113)
      - Wheeling Mold Foundry, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 114)
      - Worthington Pump Machinery, 1916-1919 (Box 3, Folder 115)
      - Youngstown Sheet Tube, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Company Visits
      - New Castle, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 117)
      - Bush Terminal, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 118)
      - Reports, 1925-1930 (Box 3, Folder 119)
      - Pittsburgh Public Schools, 1934-1942 (Box 3, Folder 120)
      - YMCA, YWCA, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 121)
      - Apprenticeship Programs, 1936-1938 (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - Reports, Meetings, and Memoranda
      - Classes, Meetings, and Campaigns, 1919-1944 (Box 3, Folder 123-129)
      - Memoranda, 1930-1932 (Box 3, Folder 130)
      - Reports, 1920-1939 (Box 3, Folder 131-135)
      - Employment Department, 1918-1944 (Box 3, Folder 136-145)
    - Labor Unions
      - Publications, 1930-1950 (Box 3, Folder 146-147)
      - Clippings, 1934-1939 (Box 3, Folder 148)
      - Correspondence, 1918-1946 (Box 3, Folder 149)
      - Plastering Union, 1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 150)
      - Railroad Station Porters, 1937-1940 (Box 3, Folder 151)
      - Domestic Service, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 152)
      - Domestic Service, Philadelphia Institute, 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 153)
      - Women's Trade Union League, 1942-1944 (Box 3, Folder 154)
      - Worker's Council, 1935-1942 (Box 3, Folder 155)
      - Worker's School, 1937-1939 (Box 3, Folder 156)
      - Negroes Strikes, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 157)
- Financial Records, III.
  Series III contains the financial records of the Urban League which consists of budgets, financial statements, and payroll records. The majority of the subgroup are the payroll records. These records concern the League staff and a series of grant programs operated during the 1960s.
  - Audits, 1930-1938 (Box 4, Folder 158)
  - Budgets, 1921-1940 (Box 4, Folder 159-163)
  - Statistical Reports, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 164)
  - Financial Statements, 1920-1932 (Box 4, Folder 165-166)
  - Payroll, 1964-1968 (Box 4, Folder 167-183)
  - Programs, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 184-192)
- Office Files, IV.
  Series IV, Office Files, consist of records that are generated during the course of daily operations of the League such as, correspondence, reports, publications, memoranda, clippings. The major topics covered are annual meetings, Camp James Weldon Johnson, relations with churches, Community Fund, contributors, history of the League, events, and files of the executive secretary from 1918-1963.
  - Administraive Material, 1.
    - Annual Meetings, 1923-1942 (Box 5, Folder 193-200)
    - Camp James Wendell Johnson, 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 201-203)
    - Churches, 1920-1943 (Box 5, Folder 204-207)
    - Community Fund Campaign, 1937-1939 (Box 5, Folder 208-210)
    - Correspondence, 1918-1941 (Box 5, Folder 211-214)
    - Executive Secretary, Reports, 1920-1933 (Box 5, Folder 215-223)
    - Executive Secretary, Correspondence, 1923 (Box 5, Folder 224)
    - Executive Secretary, Idlewild Meeting, 1921 (Box 5, Folder 225)
    - Executive Secretary, Baltimore Agencies, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 226)
    - Executive Secretary, R.M. Moss-Personal Papers, 1924-1935 (Box 5, Folder 227)
    - Fundraising, 1921-1928 (Box 5, Folder 228-232)
    - History of Urban League, 1915-1929 (Box 5, Folder 233-239)
    - Publications, 1918-1945 (Box 6, Folder 240-241)
    - Urban League Publicity, 1919-1940 (Box 6, Folder 242-245)
    - Reports, 1925-1961 (Box 6, Folder 246-250)
  - Subject Files, 2.
    - Adoption, 1919-1925 (Box 6, Folder 251)
    - Clothing, Donations, Distribution, 1925-1926 (Box 6, Folder 252)
    - Complaints, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 253)
    - Cornell Questionaire "Negro Trade Unions", 1934 (Box 6, Folder 254)
    - Credit Union, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 255)
    - Education, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 256)
    - Essay Contest, 1922 (Box 6, Folder 257)
    - Farm Sales to Negroes, 1920-1923 (Box 6, Folder 258)
    - Institutional Homes, 1927-1930 (Box 6, Folder 259-260)
    - Junior Achievement, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 261)
    - Lists of Staff, Boards, Committees (Box 6, Folder 262-263)
    - Manufacturers Sales Campaign Contest, 1923 (Box 6, Folder 264)
    - March on Washington, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 265)
    - May Fair, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 266)
    - Morals Court, 1926 (Box 6, Folder 267)
    - Mountain, Elsie Gary Red Cross, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 268)
    - Office Equipment, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 269)
    - Opportunity Magazine, 1922 (Box 6, Folder 270)
    - Post War Economic Plans, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 271)
    - Presidents Correspondence, 1920-1933 (Box 6, Folder 272-273)
    - Public Health Meeting, 1935-1938 (Box 6, Folder 274)
    - Public Relief, 1935-1938 (Box 6, Folder 275)
    - References and Recommendations, 1934-1938 (Box 6, Folder 276)
    - Rosenwald Fund, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 277)
    - Scholarship Correspondence, 1939-1942 (Box 6, Folder 278)
    - Segregation Discrimination, 1924-1932 (Box 6, Folder 279)
    - Speech Material (Box 6, Folder 280)
    - Staff Minutes, 1932-1942 (Box 6, Folder 281)
    - Memoranda, 1930-1938 (Box 6, Folder 282)
    - Resignations, 1923-1924 (Box 6, Folder 283)
    - Stanton Heights Unit, 1931-1933 (Box 6, Folder 284)
    - Statistics, 1932-1940 (Box 6, Folder 285-286)
    - Student Nurses (Box 6, Folder 287)
    - Travel Itineraries (Box 6, Folder 288)
    - Unwed Mothers, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 289)
    - Worksheets, 1926 (Box 6, Folder 290)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1919 (Box 6, Folder 291)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1920-1963 (Box 7, Folder 292-300)
    - Publications (Box 7, Folder 301-303)
- Organizations, V.
  Series V, Organizations, contains correspondence between the Urban League of Pittsburgh and national, regional and local social welfare agencies from 1915-1945. All of the organizations represented reflect the interest of the League improving conditions and employment opportunities of Pittsburgh's African-American community. Topics of special interest are the American Association of Social Workers, Negro Industrial Welfare Workers and the Industrial Baseball League organized by the League for Blacks in local factories.
  - American Association of Social Workers, 1938-1943 (Box 7, Folder 304-305)
  - American Association of Schools of Social Work Pitt Meeting, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 306)
  - American Negro Exposition, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 307)
  - Association of Negro Social Workers, 1930-1934 (Box 7, Folder 308)
  - Baltimore Camp for Underprivileged Children, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 309)
  - Big Brothers, Big Sisters, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 310)
  - Conferences and Institutes, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 311)
  - Consumer Cooperatives Publications, 1920-1940 (Box 7, Folder 312)
  - Employers Association of Pittsburgh, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 313)
  - Federation of Social Agencies, 1934-1941 (Box 7, Folder 314-316)
  - Hill District Community Council, 1936-1939 (Box 7, Folder 317-319)
  - Association for the Improvement of Social Conditions in the Hill District Consititution, 1915 (Box 7, Folder 320)
  - Housewives Cooperative League, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 321)
  - Building Maintenance Association, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 322)
  - League for Social Justice, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 323)
  - Livingston Memorial Hospital, 1933-1934 (Box 7, Folder 324)
  - Merit System League, 1937-1939 (Box 7, Folder 325)
  - National Conference of Social Work, 1924-1939 (Box 7, Folder 326-327)
  - National Negro Business League, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 328)
  - National Negro Congress, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 329)
  - National Negro Health Movement, 1927-1937 (Box 7, Folder 330)
  - Negro Businessmen's League, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 331)
  - Negro Industrial Baseball League, 1920-1923 (Box 7, Folder 332-333)
  - Negro Industrial Welfare Workers, 1918-1921 (Box 7, Folder 334-339)
  - Open Forum, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 340)
  - PA Conference on Social Work, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 341)
  - PA Security League, 1935-1936 (Box 8, Folder 342)
  - Red Cross Disaster Committee, 1942-1943 (Box 8, Folder 343)
  - Social Workers Club, 1919-1921 (Box 8, Folder 344)
  - Society of Women's Minstrel, 1921 (Box 8, Folder 345)
  - Western PA Youth Assembly, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 346)
  - World Alliance Newsletters, 1943-1945 (Box 8, Folder 347)
  - YMCA, 1935-1944 (Box 8, Folder 348-349)
  - General, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 350)
- National Urban Leagues, VI.
  Series VI, National Urban Leagues, consist of correspondence and meeting programs which reflect the active interest of the Urban League of Pittsburgh in the activities of the National Urban League from 1918-1963. Some of the subjects include the National Urban League's 25th Anniversary celebration, national annual meetings, the Vocational Opportunity Campaign, and publications and correspondence with other urban leagues.
  - 25th Anniversary, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 351-353)
  - Annual Meetings, 1918-1963 (Box 8, Folder 354-370)
  - National Vocational Opportunity Campaign, 1931-1948 (Box 8, Folder 371-380)
  - National Publications (Box 8, Folder 381-382)
  - National Emergency Advisory Council, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 383)
  - Defense Employment, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 384)
  - Memoranda, 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 385)
  - Correspondence, 1921-1929 (Box 8, Folder 386-387)
  - Affiliate Members, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 388)
  - General, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 389)
  - Cities
    - Baltimore, 1928-1942 (Box 8, Folder 390)
    - Springfield, Illinois (Box 8, Folder 391)
    - St. Paul, Minnesota (Box 8, Folder 392)
    - Kansas City, St. Louis, Missouri (Box 8, Folder 393)
    - Englewood, Newark, New Jersey (Box 8, Folder 394)
    - Akron, Canton, Cleveland, Ohio (Box 8, Folder 395)
    - Cincinnati (Box 8, Folder 396)
    - Washington D.C. (Box 8, Folder 397)
    - Correspondence with City Urban Leagues (Box 8, Folder 398)
- Government Bodies, VII.
  Series VII, Government Bodies, contains reports, statistics, minutes, and correspondence about employment discrimination, housing projects, the Civilian Conservation Corps, Works Progress Administration, and the National Youth Administration, mostly concerning the Federal government from 1917-1952. Correspondence and reports from the Pennsylvania state government concerns the employment of African-Americans and the Pennsylvania Fair Employment Practices Bill.
  - Federal, 1.
    - Apprenticeship Programs, 1940-1942 (Box 9, Folder 399)
    - Civil Service Job Announcements, 1938-1941 (Box 9, Folder 400-401)
    - Civilian Conservation Corps, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 402-403)
    - Defense Plants, 1940-1942 (Box 9, Folder 404-405)
    - Housing Programs, 1917-1952 (Box 9, Folder 406-416)
    - Department of Labor, 1919-1927 (Box 9, Folder 417-418)
    - National Youth Administration, 1935-1939 (Box 9, Folder 419-426)
    - Public Relief Publications, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 427)
    - Public Health Service Survey, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 428)
    - Works Progress Administration, 1937-1940 (Box 9, Folder 429-435)
  - Pennsylvania, 2.
    - Brown Bill Fair Employment Practice, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 436)
    - Department of Labor and Industry, 1939-1942 (Box 9, Folder 437)
    - Employment Service-Negro Department, 1919-1920 (Box 9, Folder 438-439)
    - Job Mobilization Committee Publications, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 440)
    - Temporary Commission on the Urban Colored Population, 1930 (Box 10, Folder 441-442)
    - Public Relief, 1935-1936 (Box 10, Folder 443)
    - Investigative Committees, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 444)